Bad 25 is a documentary, music film directed by Spike Lee.
Spike Lee pays tribute to Michael Jackson's Bad on the twenty-fifth anniversary of the epochal album, offering behind-the-scenes footage of Jackson recording the album
and interviews with confidants, musicians, choreographers, and such music-world superstars as Kanye West, Sheryl Crow, Cee Lo Green and Mariah Carey.
Self (archive footage), played by Michael Jackson.
Self, played by Spike Lee.
Self, played by Sheryl Crow.
Self, played by Cee Lo Green.
Self, played by Mariah Carey.
Self, played by Questlove.
Bad 25 is a 2012 documentary film about the 25th
anniversary of Michael Jackson's 1987 album Bad.
The film was directed by Spike Lee who previously directed Jackson in the music video for "They Don't
Care About Us", as well as directing the posthumous music video for the song "This Is It".
A 25th anniversary edition reissue of the Bad album was also released on
September 18, 2012, sharing the same name as the film.
The film was first screened at the 69th Venice International Film Festival on August 31, 2012 and was
shown for a limited time in New York and Los Angeles theaters on October 19, 2012.
The film made its television premiere on German television channel VOX on October
20, 2012 and in the United Kingdom on BBC2 on December 1, 2012.
A 90-minute edited version of the film, running for 64 minutes without
commercials, premiered in North America on ABC on November 22, 2012.
The film was released on Blu-ray and DVD on July 2, 2013.
The film is also available on the iTunes Store.